Register of the Albert C. Wedemeyer papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- UNITED FORCES CHINA THEATER (1944 OCTOBER-1946 SEPTEMBER) FILE, 1938-1947 (Boxes 80-91)
  - Correspondence and messages
    - Chen, Su-ho, 1945 (Box-folder 80: 23)
    - Cheng, Chien, 1944 (Box-folder 80: 24)
    - Chennault, Claire, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 1)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek and Mei-ling Soong Chiang, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 81: 2)
    - Chien, Ta-chun, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 3)
    - Chu, Chia-hua, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 4)
    - Chu Teh, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 5)
    - Churchill, Winston, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 6)
    - Clay, Lucius, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 7)
    - Cooke, Charles M., Jr., 1944 (Box-folder 81: 8)
    - Cooper, Harry, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 9)
    - Dean, Sally, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 10)
    - Donovan, William J., 1945 (Box-folder 81: 11)
    - Dorn, Frank, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 12)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 81: 13)
      Includes a letter by Dorothy Thompson to Eisenhower and a draft reply by Wedemeyer.
    - Embick, Stanley D., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 14)
    - Eng, Horace, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 15)
    - Enloe, Cortez F., Jr. and Harriet, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 16)
      Includes letters by Franklin Roosevelt and Henry L. Stimson.
    - Fairchild, Muir, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 17)
    - Ferenbaugh, Claude B., 1944 (Box-folder 81: 18)
    - Fu, Tso-ye, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 19)
    - Garrod, Guy, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 20)
    - Gillem, Alvan C., 1946 (Box-folder 81: 21)
    - Gould, Randall, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 22)
    - Handy, Thomas T., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 23)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 81: 24)
    - Ho, Hao-jo, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 81: 25)
    - Hobby, Oveta Culp, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 26)
    - Hsiao, Sin-ju Pu, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 27)
    - Hsieh, Yoh, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 28)
    - Hsu, K'an, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 29)
    - Hsu, Pei-ken, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 30)
    - Hsueh, Yueh, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 81: 31)
      Includes a letter to Claire Chennault.
    - Hu, Tsung-nan, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 32)
    - Huang, Chieh, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 33)
    - Huang, J. L., 1945 (Box-folder 81: 34)
    - Hull, J. E., 1944-1946 (Box-folder 81: 35)
    - Hurley, Patrick J., 1945-1946 (Box-folder 81: 36)
      Includes dispatches from Hurley to James Byrnes.
    - Hutchin, Claire E., 1946 (Box-folder 81: 37)
    - Ingles, H. C., 1945 (Box-folder 81: 38)
    - Ismay, Hastings, 1944 (Box-folder 81: 39)
    - Kirk, Norman, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 81: 40)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1945 (Box-folder 81: 41)
    - Koo, V. K. Wellington, 1946 (Box-folder 81: 42)
    - Ku, Chen-lung, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - Kung, H. H., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 2)
    - Kuter, Lawrence S., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 82: 3)
    - Lanham, C. T., 1946 (Box-folder 82: 4)
    - Leahy, William D., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 5)
    - LeMay, Curtis E., 1944 (Box-folder 82: 6)
    - Li, Chi-lan, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 7)
    - Li, Chung-jen, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 8)
    - Lincoln, G. A., 1944-1946 (Box-folder 82: 9)
    - Lincoln, L. J., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 82: 10)
    - Liu, Snow-pine, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 11)
    - Lovink, A. H. J., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 12)
    - Lu, Han, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 82: 13)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1946 (Box-folder 82: 14)
    - Lung, Yun, 1944 (Box-folder 82: 15)
    - Lutes, LeRoy, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 82: 16)
    - Lutze, Elizabeth M., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 17)
      Includes a letter by Henry Pownall.
    - McClure, Robert, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 82: 18)
    - McNamee, Roland W., 1945-1946 (Box-folder 82: 19)
    - Maddocks, Ray, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 20)
    - Mansfield, Mike, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 21)
    - Mao, Tse-tung, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 22)
    - Marshall, George C., 1944-1946 (Box-folder 82: 23)
      Includes a memorandum by Marshall to Dean Acheson.
    - Miller, Alice, 1944 (Box-folder 82: 24)
    - Mitchell, Robert, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 25)
    - Mountbatten, Louis, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 82: 26)
    - Murphy, Ray Livingston, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 27)
      Includes interview questions.
    - Neprud, Carl, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 28)
    - Nimitz, Chester, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 29)
    - Noble, Charles H., 1944 (Box-folder 82: 30)
    - Norstad, Lauris, 1945 (Box-folder 82: 31)
    - Overseas Press Club, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 32)
    - Patterson, Robert P., 1946 (Box-folder 82: 33)
    - Patton, George S., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 34)
    - Pechkoff, Z., 1945 (Box-folder 82: 35)
    - Pee, Peter, 1946 (Box-folder 82: 36)
    - Raeburn, Abner, 1944 (Box-folder 82: 37)
    - Roberts, Frank, 1944 (Box-folder 82: 38)
      Relates to an article about Wedemeyer by Clare Boothe Luce.
    - Robertson, Walter, 1946 (Box-folder 83: 1)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 2)
    - Sibley, Alden K., 1944 (Box-folder 83: 3)
    - Slim, W. J., 1945 (Box-folder 83: 4)
    - Somervell, Brehon, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    - Somerville, James F., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 6)
    - Soong, T. V., 1944-1946 (Box-folder 83: 7)
    - Springer, Robert M., 1944 (Box-folder 83: 8)
    - Stratemeyer, George E., 1944-1946 (Box-folder 83: 9)
    - Styer, W. D., 1944 (Box-folder 83: 10)
    - Sultan, Dan I., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 11)
    - Sun, Ching-ling Soong (Madame Sun Yat-sen), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 83: 12)
    - Tai, Li, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 13)
    - Tang, En-po, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 83: 14)
    - Teng, Hsi-hou, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 15)
    - Terry, T. A., 1945-1946 (Box-folder 83: 16)
    - Thomas, Lowell, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 17)
    - Truesdell, Karl, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 18)
    - Tu, Li-ming, 1946 (Box-folder 83: 19)
    - United States. Office of Strategic Services. China Theater [China-Burma-India Theater], 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 20)
    - United States. War Department, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 83: 21)
    - United States. White House. Letters by James A. Jacobson, Edwin A. Locke, Jr., and Donald M. Nelson, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 22)
    - Wang, Shih-chieh, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 23)
    - Waters, Jerome J., 1945 (Box-folder 83: 24)
    - Wavell, Archibald, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 25)
    - Weart, Douglas L., 1945 (Box-folder 83: 26)
    - Wedemeyer family, 1945 (Box-folder 83: 27)
    - Wei, Li-huang, 1944 (Box-folder 83: 28)
    - Wei, S. C., 1945 (Box-folder 83: 29)
      Includes a memorandum relating to Chinese military units.
    - Wei, Tao-ming, 1946 (Box-folder 83: 30)
    - Wheeler, R. A., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 31)
    - Wilby, F. B., 1944 (Box-folder 83: 32)
    - Wong, Wen-hao, 1944 (Box-folder 83: 33)
    - Wu, K. C., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 83: 34)
    - Wyman, William G., 1946 (Box-folder 83: 35)
    - Yeaton, Ivan, 1946 (Box-folder 83: 36)
      Includes a draft letter by Wedemeyer to George Marshall.
  - Maps, circa 1945 (Box-folder 83: 37)
    Includes an O.S.S. memorandum.
  - Memoranda and official messages
    - General
      - Undated (Box-folder 83: 38)
        Includes indices, 1938.
      - 1944 July - 1946 April 15 (Box-folder 83: 39-41)
      - 1946 April 16 - September (Box-folder 84: 1-4)
    - Chiang Kai-shek, from China Theater Headquarters
      - 1944 December - 1945 January (Box-folder 84: 5-7)
      - 1945 January - October (Box-folder 85: 1-6)
      - 1946 January - July (Box-folder 86: 1-2)
  - Subject file
    - General
      - General. Memoranda, notes, lists, clipping, newsletter, miscellany, and reports, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 86: 3)
        Includes a mimeograph copy of "Report of the China Theater to the Chief of Staff of the Army."
      - "Black Book," of compiled policy papers, intelligence reports, memoranda, maps, and mission summaries, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 86: 4-6)
    - African-American soldiers. Memoranda, messages, clipping, meeting reports, and correspondence with Patrick Hurley, 1945 (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - Birch, John. Report relating to the death of Birch, 1945 (Box-folder 87: 2)
    - China
      - General. Pamphlets and miscellany, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 87: 3)
      - Foreign relations. Mimeograph speech transcript by Chiang Kai-shek, treaty texts, and printed article, 1945 (Box-folder 87: 4)
        Primarily relates to the Sino-Soviet Treaty of Friendship and Alliance. See also: United States-Foreign relations/China.
      - Politics and government
        - General. Typescripts, chart, and mimeograph reports, 1944 - circa 1946 (Box-folder 87: 5)
          Includes typescript copies of "Brief Delineation of the Subdivisions of the KMT," and "Personal Observations of Chiang Kai-shek, 1926-1945," and a mimeograph copy of John S. Service, "The Need for Greater Realism in Our Relations with Chiang Kai-shek."
        - Chinese communists
          See also: Yenan Observer Group.
          - General, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 87: 6)
            Memoranda, correspondence with Chiang Kai-shek and Mao Tse-tung, meeting minutes, draft press release, speech by Earl Browder, typescript report by Paul Linebarger, newsletter, and typescript copies of "A Memorandum on the Problem of the Chinese Communist Party," and "Will Russia Supercede Japan as Aggressor in the Orient."
          - "Chinese Communists in Relation to Planned Military Operations in China," mimeograph report, 1945 April (Box-folder 87: 7)
    - Conferences. Protocol, U.N. charter text, communiqués, press release, and memoranda, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 87: 8)
    - Dorn, Frank. Letters, reports, and messages, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 87: 9)
    - France. Langer, William L. "Our Vichy Policy and the North African Venture,", 1946 January
      - Chapters 1-3 (Box-folder 87: 10-11)
      - Chapters 4-9 (Box-folder 88: 1-6)
    - Germany. Koehler, General, "The Collapse Viewed from Within: The Memoirs of General Koller [sic], the German Chief of Air Staff,", 1945 (Box-folder 88: 7)
    - Hurley, Patrick. Printed article and typescript meeting report, 1945 (Box-folder 88: 8)
    - Institute of Pacific Relations. Clippings, miscellany, and letters by Alfred Kohlberg and another, 1942-1946 (Box-folder 88: 9)
    - Japan. Printed article and notes, 1944 (Box-folder 88: 10)
    - Japanese capitulation. Memoranda, messages, flyer, and policy papers, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      Includes information relating to the repatriation of Japanese citizens.
    - Japanese war crimes trials. Draft typescript review of record of trial of Masataka Kaburagi, et al., 1946 (Box-folder 89: 2)
    - Korea. Pamphlet and flyer issued by the Korean Commission, 1945 (Box-folder 89: 3)
    - Manchuria, 1946 (Box-folder 89: 4)
      Map, clippings, speeches and statements by Chou En-lai and Walter Judd, memorandum, messages, and typescript reports, "Special Summary of Intelligence on Manchuria," and O. Edmund Clubb,"Relationship of Japanese, and Particularly Japanese Holdout Troops, to Chinese Communist Actions in Manchuria," "Relationship of Koreans and Mongols to Communist Movement in Manchuria," and "Soviet Policies, Attitudes and Actions in Respect to Manchuria."
    - Military planning. Meeting report, and outline reports, "Far East Strategy," and "Plan for Evacuation of China,", 1945 (Box-folder 89: 5)
    - Nuclear weapons. Statement by Bernard Baruch, comments on the Baruch report by Joseph V. Machugh, and mimeograph reports by Leslie R. Groves, Matthew B. Ridgway and others, 1946 (Box-folder 89: 6)
    - Peace treaties. Clipping and messages conveying draft treaty texts, 1946 (Box-folder 89: 7)
    - Southeast Asia, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 90: 1-2)
      Memoranda, messages, intelligence questionnaires, typescript copies of "Franco-Chinese Agreement Concerning Sino-Indochinese Relations," and "Agreement on the General Principle on the Taking over of Garrison Duty by the French Troops from the Chinese Forces Stationed in Indo-China," and mimeograph copies of "Development of the I.W.T. on the River Chindwin, 1945," "Political Situation in South East Asia Since Surrender of Japan," "Possible Japanese Action in Siam," "Economic Situation in South East Asia," and "Military Situation in South East Asia."
      See also: Correspondence/Browning, F. A. M. and Mountbatten, Louis; CHIEF OF STAFF FILE/ Correspondence/ Mountbatten, Louis; and SIXTH UNITED STATES ARMY FILE/Subject File/World War II/Southeast Asia Command.
    - Soviet Union. Mimeograph and typescript reports, clipping, memorandum, and letter from Robert Patterson to Harry Truman, 1946 (Box-folder 90: 3)
    - United States-Armed Forces-Management. Memoranda and typescript report, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 90: 4)
      Includes material relating to military organization and to cooperation between the China Theater and the India-Burma Theater.
    - United States-Foreign relations
      - General. Clippings, newsletters, speeches by Patrick J. Hurley and Harry S. Truman, and a typescript copy of "A Security Policy for Postwar America,", 1945-1946 (Box-folder 90: 5)
      - China
        - General, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 90: 6)
          Memoranda, messages, clippings, serial issue, letters by Alfred Kohlberg and others, mimeograph copies of the State-War-Navy [Departments] Coordinating Committee, "Post-War Military Policies with Respect to China," speech by Walter Judd, statements by James Byrnes and Harry S. Truman, and typescript copies of Albert S. Crockett, "The Chinese-American 'Alliance' of 1908," Owen Lattimore, "Japan Policy as Related to China Policy," and Freda Utley, "General Marshall's Failure in China or Time for a Change in China."
        - Economic assistance, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 90: 7-8)
          Memoranda, maps, typescript copies of "Production in China," "Progress and Status of Export-Import Bank Credits to China," "Statement on Surplus Property, Lend-Lease, etc.," John F. Kullgren, "The Need of an Economic Nucleus-Area in China: The Case of the Yellow River Area, the Provinces East of the Yellow River Bend," mimeograph copies of comments on Kullgren's report by the U.S. Embassy staff in Nanking, Paul M. A. Linebarger, "Specific Recommendations Concerning Aid to China," Edwin A. Locke, Jr.,"The Current Situation in China," Carl Neprud, "Resume of the Economic Situation in Shanghai Since Re-opening of Customs," Shou-Chin Wang, "Application for Export-Import Bank Credit on Four Development Projects by the Chinese Government," "Development Projects Contemplated by the Chinese Government," and "Initial Reconstruction Program for China," and correspondence with Neprud, Locke, Paul S. Hopkins and Wang.
        - Military assistance, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 91: 1-2)
          Memoranda, messages, draft legislation, speeches and statements by Ching-ling Soong Sun (Madame Sun Yat-sen), clipping, Chinese communist press releases, clippings, typescript copies of "Intelligence Plan for Post-War China," and "Strength and Composition of Chinese Air Force," and correspondence with Paul W. Caraway, Ho Ying-chin, George C. Marshall, Carl Spaatz and others.
      - Soviet Union. Bulletins of the American-Russian Chamber of Commerce, printed excerpt, reports by Bland Calder, George Kennan and others, and a letter to Calder, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 91: 3)
    - United States. Army Air Forces. 14th Air Force. Notes, memoranda, and letters by Claire Chennault and J. Hart Caughey, 1943-1946 (Box-folder 91: 4)
    - United States. Navy Group in China. Memoranda, messages, and a letter to Richard P. Heppner (O.S.S.), 1944-1947 (Box-folder 91: 5)
    - United States. Army. Services of Supply
      - General. Memoranda and correspondence with Henry S. Aurand, Gilbert X. Cheves and others, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 91: 6)
      - Radio station. Memoranda, messages, and letters by Henry S. Aurand, 1945 (Box-folder 91: 7)
    - Yenan Observer Group (Dixie Mission). Memoranda and correspondence with Ivan Yeaton and others, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 91: 8)
  - Trips. Schedules, typescript report, and maps, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 91: 9)
- SECOND UNITED STATES ARMY (1946 SEPTEMBER-1947 OCTOBER) FILE, 1935-1950 (Boxes 92-97)
  Memoranda, correspondence, speeches, reports, memoranda, notes, printed material, treaty texts, dispatches, press releases, and miscellany, arranged by form, thereunder by subject.
  - General. Memoranda and diary entries, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 1)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 2)
    - Abernathy, John A., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 3)
    - Allan, C. V., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 4)
    - Alsop, Joseph, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 5)
    - Anderberg, Edward, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 6)
    - Andrews, W. G., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 7)
    - Avshalomoff, A., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 8)
    - Barr, David G., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 9)
    - Barrett, David, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 10)
    - Bartlett, Boyd, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 11)
    - Baxter, R. W., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 12)
    - Bissell, Clayton, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 13)
    - Bivins, Luther M., 1946 (Box-folder 92: 14)
    - Blake, Ralph, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 15)
    - Brink, Francis G., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 16)
    - Brown, Constantine, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 17)
    - Byers, Clovis, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 18)
    - Cairns, Huntington, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 19)
    - Calder, Bland, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 20)
    - Caraway, Paul W., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 21)
    - Carter, Craig W., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 22)
    - Caughey, Hart, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 23)
    - Chang, Carsun, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 24)
    - Chang, Fa-kwei, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 25)
    - Chang, P. H., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 26)
    - Chen, Cheng, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 27)
    - Chen, Chih-mai, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 28)
    - Chen, K. P., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 29)
    - Chen, Y. Y., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 30)
    - Cheng, Kai-min, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 31)
    - Chennault, Claire L., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 32)
    - Chiang, Chao-ho, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 33)
    - Chiang, Kai-shek and Mei-ling Soong Chiang, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 34)
    - Chilikin, V. A., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 35)
    - Chin, Cheng, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 36)
    - Chinese Farmers' Party (S. T. Tung), 1947 (Box-folder 92: 37)
    - Chu, Auyang, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 38)
    - Clay, Lucius, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 39)
    - Cline, Ray S., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 40)
    - Clubb, O. Edmund, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 41)
    - Compton, Karl, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 42)
    - Conners, Bradley, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 43)
    - Creasy, William M., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 44)
    - Dallin, David J., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 45)
    - Dau, Frederick J., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 46)
    - Davis, Monnett, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 47)
    - Davis, Spencer, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 48)
    - Davis, Tommy, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 49)
    - Deford, Earl, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 50)
    - Demobilized Interpreting Officers Association, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 51)
    - Devers, Jacob L., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 52)
    - Dewey, Bradley, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 53)
    - Donovan, William J., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 54)
    - Dzau, Linson, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 55)
    - Dzung, Kenyon V., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 56)
    - Eddy, Manton S., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 57)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 58)
    - Elias, Fred S., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 59)
    - Embick, Stanley D., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 60)
    - Enloe, Cortez F., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 61)
    - Evans, Upshur, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 62)
    - Figl, Leopold, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 63)
    - Fitch, Geraldine, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 64)
    - Folster, George, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 65)
    - Forrestal, James, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 66)
    - Freeman, Fulton, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 67)
    - Gailey, Charles K., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 68)
    - Gayle, Richard B., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 69)
    - German League for Human Rights, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 70)
    - Gilbertson, Ralph O., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 71)
    - Gillem, Alvan C., Jr., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 72)
      Includes letters by Francis Brink, Harry C. Eckhoff and others.
    - Gin, Tse-long, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 92: 73)
    - Glasgow, Bill, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 74)
    - Goode, Paul R., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 75)
    - Gould, Randall, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 76)
    - Gruenther, Alfred, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 77)
    - Handy, Thomas T., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 78)
    - Harriman, W. Averell, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 79)
    - Ho, Ying-chin, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 80)
    - Hodge, John R., 1947 (Box-folder 92: 81)
    - Hoover, J. Edgar, 1947 (Box-folder 92: 82)
    - Hsiao, Chin-Meng, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 1)
    - Hsiung, Shih-hui, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 2)
    - Huang, M., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 3)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 4)
    - Hull, J. E., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 5)
      Includes a letter by Francis Brink.
    - Hurley, Patrick, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 6)
    - Hutchin, C. E., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 7)
    - Jacobs, Joseph E., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 8)
    - Jacobson, J. E., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 9)
    - Kauffman, J. L., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 10)
    - Keenan, Gregory F., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 11)
    - Keightley, Charles, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 12)
    - Kerr, George H., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 13)
    - Keswick, John, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 14)
    - King, Louise (Mrs. Woods King), 1947 (Box-folder 93: 15)
    - Kingstone, Marina S., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 16)
    - Koch, Adelbert, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 17)
    - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 18)
      Includes letters by Arthur Vandenberg.
    - Korean Women's Nationalist Party, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 19)
    - Krause, George H., 1946 (Box-folder 93: 20)
    - Kuebart, Martin, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 21)
    - Kullgren, John, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 22)
    - Lamb, Samuel S., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 23)
    - Lea, Thomas S., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 24)
    - Leahy, William D., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 25)
    - Lee, James H., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 26)
    - Lemnitzer, Louis L., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 27)
    - Lewis, John T., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 28)
    - Li, Chai-sum, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 29)
    - Li, Han-yuan, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 30)
    - Li, Tsung-jen, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 31)
    - Liao, Yao-siang, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 32)
    - Linebarger, Paul M. A., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 33)
    - Lipsman, J. G., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 34)
    - Litter, D. H., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 35)
    - Liu, Snow-pine, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 36)
    - Liu, Teh Ming, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 37)
    - Lovett, Robert A., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 38)
    - Lu, Han, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 39)
    - Lucas, John P., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 40)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 41)
    - Luce, Henry R., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 42)
    - Luedemann, Rudolf, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 43)
    - MacArthur, Douglas, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 44)
    - McClure, Robert B., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 45)
    - McCune, Shannon, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 46)
    - McKelway, B. M., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 47)
    - Mahon, E. J., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 48)
    - Marshall, George C., 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 49)
    - Meyer, Paul, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 50)
    - Meyer, Robert, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 51)
    - Miller, Adelhail, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 52)
    - Miller, Jack R., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 53)
    - Milton, B., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 54)
    - Moorad, George, 1946 (Box-folder 93: 55)
    - Moore, Merrill, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 56)
    - Mountbatten, Louis, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 93: 57)
    - Muggeridge, Malcolm, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 58)
    - Murphy, Paul, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 59)
    - Neprud, Carl, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 60)
    - Noble, C. H., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 61)
    - Oexle, C. W., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 62)
    - Olds, Archie, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 63)
    - Ouang, Max and Eppy, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 64)
    - Pan, Stephen Chao-ying, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 65)
    - Parks, F. L., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 66)
    - Parsons, Arthur M., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 67)
    - Patterson, Paul, 1946 (Box-folder 93: 68)
    - Patterson, Robert P., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 69)
    - Peck, Walter R., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 70)
    - Pee, Peter, 1946 (Box-folder 93: 71)
    - Petersen, Howard C., 1947 (Box-folder 93: 72)
    - Pi, Chung-kan, 1946 (Box-folder 93: 73)
    - Pirnie, W. Bruce, 1947 (Box-folder 93: 74)